Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
Hi everyone.
大家好。
My name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
What do you got, Catherine, for us today?
Catherine，你今天给我们带来了什么？
That's a good question.
这是个好问题。
Well, we've got a little bit of a Seinfeld situation.
嗯，我们有一个有点像《宋飞正传》里的情景。
So, for those of you who are not familiar with this American TV show, which, by the
所以，对于那些不熟悉这部美国电视剧的朋友们，顺便说一句，
way, is one of my favorites, Seinfeld is a TV show, a comedy, about very awkward, very
这是我最喜欢的剧之一，《宋飞正传》是一部喜剧，讲的是一些非常尴尬、
common situations that are taken to the extreme.
非常常见但被夸张到极致的情景。
Right.
没错。
So, it's a very popular show.
所以，这是一部非常受欢迎的剧。
It was around for like 10 years, I think.
它大概播了十年左右，我想。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
But it's not airing anymore.
但现在不再播出了。
Well, they're not making new episodes anymore.
嗯，他们不再制作新剧集了。
No, you have to see them in reruns.
不，你只能在重播里看到它们。
Reruns, right.
重播，没错。
So, we have a situation that's very common and it was pretty funny on the show.
所以，我们有一个非常常见的情景，在剧里还挺搞笑的。
It's a guy trying to rent a car.
是一个男人想租车。
Okay, so he's probably at the airport or traveling and he's had a long flight and he wants to
好的，所以他可能是在机场或者旅行中，刚经历长途飞行，想
rent a car, but of course, there are some problems.
租辆车，但当然，遇到了一些问题。
So, this is an elementary level lesson, by the way.
顺便说一下，这是一个初级水平的课程。
So keep that in mind as we listen to this dialogue one time.
所以在我们听一遍这段对话时，请记住这一点。
Hi, I made a reservation for a mid-size vehicle.
你好，我预订了一辆中型车。
The name is Jimmy Fox.
名字是Jimmy Fox。
I'm sorry, we have no mid-size available at the moment.
抱歉，我们现在没有中型车可用。
I don't understand.
我不明白。
I made a reservation.
我预订了。
Do you have my reservation?
你们有我的预订记录吗？
Yes, we do.
是的，我们有。
Unfortunately, we ran out of cars.
不幸的是，我们的车都租完了。
But the reservation keeps the car here.
但预订应该能保留车在这里。
That's why you have the reservation.
这就是为什么要有预订。
I know why we have reservations.
我知道为什么要有预订。
I don't think you do.
我觉得你不知道。
If you did, I'd have a car.
如果你知道，我就该有车了。
See, you know how to take the reservation.
你看，你知道怎么接受预订。
You just don't know how to hold the reservation and that's really the most important part
你就是不知道怎么保留预订，而这才是预订最重要的部分，
of the reservation, the holding.
保留。
Anybody can just take them.
谁都能接受预订。
But we do have a compact or an SUV if you'd like.
但我们有紧凑型车或SUV，如果你想要的话。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll take the compact.
我就要紧凑型车。
All right.
好的。
We have a blue Ford Focus for you, Mr. Fox.
我们有一辆蓝色福特福克斯给您，Fox先生。
Would you like insurance?
您要买保险吗？
Yeah, you better give me the insurance because I'm going to beat the hell out of this car.
是的，你最好给我保险，因为我要把这车往死里开。
All right, great.
好的，没问题。
So this actually happens a lot.
所以这种情况其实经常发生。
You make a reservation and either they lose it or they run out of cars.
你做了预订，要么他们弄丢了，要么车租完了。
It's such a common situation.
这真是个常见的情况。
And it's not just cars.
而且不只是车。
Sometimes this happens at restaurants too and it really makes me angry.
有时餐厅也会这样，这真的让我很生气。
Yeah, that happens a lot.
是啊，经常发生。
You show up and they're like, oh, we don't have a reservation.
你到了，他们就说，哦，我们没有你的预订。
And you're just like...
然后你就只能……
Well, then you have to keep yourself in check.
嗯，那你得控制住自己。
You can't really get angry.
你不能真的生气。
But this guy does.
但这个人就生气了。
So let's take a look at the language takeaway to find out what are some of the words we're
所以让我们看看语言要点，找出我们在这里用来描述租车
using here to describe renting a car and what kind of car we're talking about.
以及谈论车型的一些词汇。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, as you mentioned, at rental places, they have different size cars, right?
嗯，正如你提到的，在租车公司，他们有不同大小的车，对吧？
Different size vehicles.
不同大小的车辆。
Which, by the way, costs different prices.
顺便说一下，价格也不同。
Right.
没错。
So let's take a look at the sizes that they mentioned in dialogue.
所以让我们看看对话中提到的车型大小。
Starting with the cheapest one, the least expensive and the smallest, it's a compact
从最便宜的、最便宜也最小的开始，是紧凑型
vehicle.
车辆。
All right, compact.
好的，紧凑型。
So compact actually means small.
所以compact实际上意思是小的。
Small.
小的。
Right.
没错。
So compact car, you're going to hear very often.
所以紧凑型车，你会经常听到。
Even if you're buying a car, let's think of an...
即使你买车，让我们想想一个……
What's a compact car?
什么是紧凑型车？
The VW Golf is a compact car, very small car.
大众高尔夫就是紧凑型车，非常小的车。
So usually it's two doors or if it's a four door car, it's very small, not very long,
所以通常是两门，或者如果是四门车，也很小，不太长，
right?
对吧？
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So maybe like a Ford Focus could be a small car, a compact.
所以比如福特福克斯可能算小型车，紧凑型。
Now moving up in size a little bit, we would have a midsize vehicle.
现在稍微大一点，我们有中型车辆。
Okay, midsize vehicle is...
好的，中型车辆是……
Well, it's a giveaway here because mid means middle.
嗯，这很明显，因为mid意思是中间。
So it's kind of in the middle between the small and the large.
所以它介于小型和大型之间。
And this is your average four door sedan car.
这就是你常见的四门轿车。
Okay.
好的。
So as an example, you would have a Ford Taurus or maybe a Toyota Camry.
举个例子，比如福特金牛座或者丰田凯美瑞。
Yeah, Toyota Camry is maybe the most common car.
是的，丰田凯美瑞可能是最常见的车。
Yeah.
嗯。
It's kind of expensive, but it's still midsize, right?
它有点贵，但还是中型车，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And now a bigger car and probably one of the most popular cars in the United States is
而现在更大的车，可能是美国最受欢迎的车之一，是
an SUV.
SUV。
Not anymore, Marco.
现在不是了，Marco。
I know.
我知道。
Yeah, the energy crisis and the...
是啊，能源危机和……
Gas prices.
油价。
Well, and the economy as well.
嗯，还有经济因素。
People are not driving their SUVs anymore.
人们不再开他们的SUV了。
But SUV is an acronym.
但SUV是一个首字母缩写。
That means it stands for three different words.
意思是它代表三个不同的单词。
S meaning...
S代表……
Sports.
运动。
U meaning...
U代表……
Utility.
多功能。
V...
V……
Vehicle.
车辆。
All right.
好的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So SUV, sport utility vehicle, means it can go maybe off-road.
所以SUV，运动型多功能车，意味着它可以越野。
Right.
没错。
So an example of this would be a Ford Explorer or...
举个例子，比如福特探险者或者……
Jeep Cherokee.
吉普切诺基。
A Jeep Cherokee could be an SUV as well.
吉普切诺基也可以是SUV。
That's right.
没错。
Those are three different types of cars.
这是三种不同类型的车。
Now obviously there are many more like a van or a...
现在显然还有很多其他类型，比如面包车或者……
A limo.
豪华轿车。
A limo, like a limousine.
一辆豪华轿车，就像 limousine 那种。
But yeah, these are the most common ones that you would rent at a car rental place.
不过，这些是你在租车公司最常租到的车型。
Yeah, definitely.
没错，确实如此。
But what we have to do here is make a reservation.
但我们现在要做的是预订。
Now interesting, you make a reservation.
有意思，你说“make a reservation”。
Yeah, you don't have it.
对，你还没有车。
You don't do it.
你不是“做”车。
You don't...
你不是……
You make it.
你是“做”预订。
Yeah, you make...
对，你“做”……
These are words that go together.
这些是固定搭配的词。
So we're going to keep them together.
所以我们要把它们放在一起记。
I can call a restaurant.
我可以给餐厅打电话。
So say for example, Marco works at a restaurant.
比如说，Marco 在一家餐厅工作。
I say, hello, I'd like to make a reservation for tonight.
我说，你好，我想预订今晚的位子。
Oh, okay.
哦，好的。
Perfect.
完美。
Now if you show up at the restaurant, you say...
如果你到了餐厅，你说……
Where's my table?
我的桌子呢？
I made a reservation.
我预订过了。
Right.
对。
And of course I throw a fit because there's no table for me.
当然我会大发脾气，因为没给我留桌子。
So you make a reservation and in this case it was made before.
所以你“make a reservation”，而且这次是提前预订的。
Okay, so you make a reservation.
好的，所以是“make a reservation”。
Now why was this guy angry at the rental car place?
那这个人为什么在租车公司生气？
Oh, long story short, the company ran out of cars.
哦，长话短说，公司没车了。
Not all cars, just the car that he wanted, the mid-size vehicle.
不是所有车，只是他想要的那种中型车。
So they ran out.
所以他们“ran out”了。
So that doesn't mean they're actually running somewhere.
但这不意味着他们真的在跑步。
No, they're not putting on their running shoes and going for a jog.
不，他们没穿上跑鞋去慢跑。
Now in this case, to run out or in this case, we ran out means that they don't have any
在这个例子里，“run out”或“we ran out”意思是他们没有……
more.
更多了。
You don't have any more.
你没有了。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So, I think it is a nice word for us to take a look at some other examples now.
所以，我觉得这是个好词，我们来看看其他例子。
Example one.
例子一。
We're going to run out of gasoline.
我们的汽油快用完了。
We need to find a gas station soon.
我们得尽快找个加油站。
Example two.
例子二。
Can you buy some milk on your way home?
你能在回家的路上买点牛奶吗？
We ran out last night.
我们昨晚用完了。
Example three.
例子三。
My pen ran out of ink.
我的笔没墨了。
Can you lend me one, please?
能借我一支吗？
Not a fun phrase, but an important one in case you're ever in a restaurant or in a hotel
这不是个有趣的短语，但很重要，万一你在餐厅、酒店或任何可以购买或租东西的地方，东西全没了。
or in a place where you can purchase something or rent something and it's all gone.
全没了。
All right.
好的。
So, I think we've taken a look at a lot of great words here.
所以，我觉得我们看了很多好词。
So let's listen to this dialogue again.
那我们再听一遍这段对话。
We're going to slow it down just a little bit and then we'll come back and explain some
我们会稍微放慢速度，然后回来解释一些……
phrases.
短语。
Hi, I made a reservation for a mid-size vehicle.
你好，我预订了一辆中型车。
The name is Jimmy Fox.
名字是 Jimmy Fox。
I'm sorry.
抱歉。
We have no mid-size available at the moment.
我们现在没有中型车可用。
I don't understand.
我不明白。
I made a reservation.
我预订了。
Do you have my reservation?
你们有我的预订记录吗？
Yes, we do.
有的。
Unfortunately, we ran out of cars.
不幸的是，我们的车用完了。
But the reservation keeps the car here.
但预订应该把车留在这里。
That's why you have the reservation.
这就是预订的意义。
I know why we have reservations.
我知道预订的意义。
I don't think you do.
我觉得你不知道。
If you did, I'd have a car.
如果你知道，我就有车了。
See, you know how to take the reservation.
你看，你知道怎么接受预订。
You just don't know how to hold the reservation.
你就是不知道怎么保留预订。
And that's really the most important part of the reservation, the holding.
而这才是预订最重要的部分——保留。
Anybody can just take them.
任何人都能接受预订。
But we do have a compact or an SUV if you'd like.
但我们有紧凑型车或SUV，如果您想要的话。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll take the compact.
我就要紧凑型车。
All right.
好的。
We have a blue Ford Focus for you, Mr. Fox.
我们有一辆蓝色福特福克斯给您，Fox先生。
Would you like insurance?
您要保险吗？
Yeah, you better give me the insurance because I'm going to beat the hell out of this car.
是的，你最好给我保险，因为我要把这车往死里开。
And we're back.
我们回来了。
So, Marco, we've got a couple of phrases here that deserve some attention.
所以，Marco，这里有几个短语值得注意。
So let's take a look at them in today's Fluency Builder.
那我们来看看今天的流利度提升环节。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
So, the first phrase that I want to take a look at is when the agent says, I'm sorry,
所以，我想看的第一个短语是当工作人员说：“抱歉，我们现在没有中型车可用。”
we have no mid-size available at the moment.
“我们现在没有中型车可用。”
Okay.
好的。
So do they or do they not have any?
所以他们到底有没有？
Yeah.
有。
She says, we have no mid-size.
她说：“我们没有中型车。”
Okay.
好的。
So another way to say this is, we haven't got any.
另一种说法是：“我们没有任何车。”
Or we don't have any.
或者“我们没有。”
Okay.
好的。
But in this case, you can just simplify it and say, we have no.
但在这个例子里，你可以简化说“我们没有”。
Why wouldn't you say we have none?
为什么不说“我们一个都没有”？
Good question.
好问题。
Why?
为什么？
Because we need a thing here.
因为这里需要加个东西。
We have no cars.
我们没有车。
We have no cake.
我们没有蛋糕。
We have no food.
我们没有食物。
So this is a very common phrase in English.
所以这是英语中很常见的短语。
And remember to put the thing at the end.
记住要把东西放在最后。
So for example, can I say, I have no money?
比如，我能说“我没钱”吗？
Absolutely.
当然可以。
I'm so sorry, Marco, but I'm not going to lend you any.
很抱歉，Marco，但我不会借给你。
I have no money.
我没钱。
Seriously, lend me some money.
说真的，借我点钱。
So we have no.
所以是“我们没有”。
This is interesting because this is not a structure that is usually learned through
这很有意思，因为这不是通常从教科书里学到的结构，对吧？
textbooks, right?
对。
You usually say, I don't have or we haven't got.
你通常会说“我没有”或“我们没有”。
Exactly.
完全正确。
This is very spoken because you would never say, I go no.
这很口语化，因为你永远不会说“我去没有”。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Right.
对。
We're not knowing that we, that has an object, something that we have.
我们不知道我们，它有个宾语，我们拥有的东西。
So here, I have no is very spoken, very common.
所以这里，“我没有”很口语化，很常见。
It's got another phrase that is also not taught so much in those textbooks that we were just
还有另一个短语，在我们刚才提到的那些教科书里也不太教。
mentioning.
对。
So what's that phrase at the end?
那结尾的短语是什么？
Well, well.
嗯，嗯。
It's a threat.
这是一种威胁。
The guy is so angry.
这家伙非常生气。
He leans over the counter and he points his finger in the agent's face.
他俯身靠在柜台上，用手指指着代理的脸。
And what does he say?
他说了什么？
He says, yeah, you better give me the insurance.
他说，是啊，你最好给我保险。
You better.
你最好。
All right.
好吧。
So you better than me.
所以你比我好。
No, no.
不，不。
It's not like better, like something is good, right?
这不是“更好”那种意思，像某样东西很好，对吧？
You'd better is like a suggestion, but a very strong one.
“你最好”像是一个建议，但非常强烈。
Okay.
好的。
Very strong.
非常强烈。
This is a threat.
这是一种威胁。
Yeah.
是的。
You better eat your dinner or I'm going to send you to your room.
你最好吃完你的晚餐，否则我就把你送到你房间去。
Exactly.
没错。
So as you can see, it says, he says, you better, you better give me the insurance.
所以你看，它说，他说，你最好，你最好给我保险。
But the grammatically correct way would be.
但语法上正确的说法是。
You had better.
你最好（had better）。
So the contraction would be you'd better.
所以缩写形式是“你'd better”。
Exactly.
没错。
You'd, you had better do this.
你'd，你最好做这个。
So this is a, it's a hypothetical situation.
所以这是一个假设的情况。
You had better do this.
你最好做这个。
If you don't do this, bad things will happen.
如果你不做这个，坏事就会发生。
So remember that here we've got the grammatically correct form that you should write.
所以记住，这里我们有语法上正确的形式，你应该写。
You'd better or the spoken form.
你'd better 或者口语形式。
You better.
你 better。
I think in this one, we should also listen to some other examples to get a better idea
我想在这个例子里，我们也应该听一些其他例子，以便更好地理解。
of how we can use this very strong suggestion.
我们如何使用这个非常强烈的建议。
Example one.
例子一。
You better go to the doctor before that cold gets any worse.
你最好在感冒恶化之前去看医生。
Example two.
例子二。
You better watch out.
你最好小心点。
It's dangerous to go out this late.
这么晚出去很危险。
Example three.
例子三。
She better change her attitude or her boss is going to fire her.
她最好改变态度，否则她的老板会解雇她。
So what is the threat?
那么威胁是什么？
You better give me insurance because what is he going to do?
你最好给我保险，因为他要做什么？
He says, I'm going to beat the hell out of this car.
他说，我要把这辆车打个稀巴烂。
Okay, so this is future.
好的，所以这是将来时。
I'm going to, I'm gonna.
我要，我 gonna。
Right.
对。
Beat the hell out of this car.
把这辆车打个稀巴烂。
So this is very strong, right?
所以这非常强烈，对吧？
Yeah, it's very strong.
是的，非常强烈。
And he's saying he is going to destroy the car.
他说他要毁掉这辆车。
So beat the hell out of.
所以“beat the hell out of”。
That means really just do damage to something.
意思就是真的对某物造成损坏。
So you can use it towards a person also.
你也可以用它来形容一个人。
It's like, I'm going to beat the hell out of you.
就像，我要把你打个稀巴烂。
And I'll arrest you for violence.
我会以暴力罪名逮捕你。
Right.
对。
So it's a very strong phrase.
所以这是一个非常强烈的短语。
It shows anger.
它表示愤怒。
It shows that you are threatening somebody.
它表示你在威胁某人。
So it's not, obviously it's not polite.
所以显然它不礼貌。
And it might get you a broken nose in a bar if you ever say this to someone or about someone.
如果你对某人或关于某人说这个，可能会在酒吧里让你鼻梁骨折。
So be very careful.
所以要非常小心。
Right.
对。
But you can use it to describe a situation, right?
但你可以用它来描述一个情况，对吧？
It's like, yeah, we went to a bar yesterday and Dan beat the hell out of the bartender.
就像，是啊，我们昨天去了一个酒吧，丹把酒保打了个稀巴烂。
Right?
对吧？
Man.
天啊。
So instead of just saying Dan hit the bartender or Dan got into a fight, you're saying he
所以不只是说丹打了酒保或丹打架了，而是说他。
hit him and he just.
打了他，而且他。
And he kept hitting him and kept hitting him and kept hitting him.
他不停地打他，不停地打他，不停地打他。
So yeah, he beat the hell out of him.
所以是的，他把他打了个稀巴烂。
Right.
对。
All right, great.
好的，很好。
So those are the phrases and words that we wanted to talk about today.
所以这些就是我们今天想讨论的短语和单词。
But I think it'd be good if we listen to this dialogue one more time just to get a good
但我认为我们最好再听一遍这段对话，以便更好地。
feel for it.
感受它。
When we come back, we'll be talking a little bit more about the process of renting a car.
我们回来时，会再聊一点关于租车的过程。
Hi, I made a reservation for a midsize vehicle.
嗨，我预订了一辆中型车。
The name is Jimmy Fox.
名字是吉米·福克斯。
I'm sorry, we have no midsize available at the moment.
抱歉，我们现在没有中型车可用。
I don't understand.
我不明白。
I made a reservation.
我预订了。
Do you have my reservation?
你们有我的预订吗？
Yes, we do.
是的，我们有。
Unfortunately, we ran out of cars.
不幸的是，我们的车用完了。
But the reservation keeps the car here.
但预订应该保留车在这里。
That's why you have the reservation.
这就是为什么你要预订。
I know why we have reservations.
我知道为什么要有预订。
I don't think you do.
我觉得你不知道。
If you did, I'd have a car.
如果你知道，我就有车了。
See, you know how to take the reservation.
你看，你知道怎么接受预订。
You just don't know how to hold the reservation.
你就是不知道怎么保留预订。
And that's really the most important part of the reservation.
而这才是预订最重要的部分。
The holding.
保留。
Anybody can just take them.
任何人都可以接受它们。
But we do have a compact or an SUV if you'd like.
但我们有紧凑型车或SUV，如果你想要的话。
Fine, I'll take the compact.
好吧，我就要紧凑型车。
All right.
好的。
We have a blue Ford Focus for you, Mr. Fox.
我们有一辆蓝色福特福克斯给你，福克斯先生。
Would you like insurance?
你想要保险吗？
Yeah, you better give me the insurance because I'm going to beat the hell out of this car.
是啊，你最好给我保险，因为我要把这辆车打个稀巴烂。
You know, I heard that in Florida or in certain like cities of California and Florida, you
你知道吗，我听说在佛罗里达或某些像加州和佛罗里达的城市，你。
can actually rent luxury cars.
实际上可以租豪华车。
Oh, yeah, you can do that in most places.
哦，是的，大多数地方都可以。
You can rent like a Porsche or a Lamborghini or a Ferrari.
你可以租像保时捷、兰博基尼或法拉利这样的车。
Yeah, obviously it costs a lot of money, but it gives you the opportunity to maybe drive
是的，显然这要花很多钱，但它给了你机会去开。
one of these cars that you obviously wouldn't have the money to buy.
这些你显然买不起的车。
Yeah, especially if you're talking about those warm places like Florida, California, you
是的，特别是如果你说的是那些温暖的地方，比如佛罗里达、加州，你。
want to be in the sunshine, you get a convertible.
想享受阳光，你会租一辆敞篷车。
You got to get a convertible.
你必须租一辆敞篷车。
Yeah, so I think the insurance premiums on those particular cars are very high though.
是的，所以我想那些特定车的保险费非常高。
So you're not only paying for the car, but you're also paying for the insurance and possibly
所以你不仅要付车钱，还要付保险，可能还有。
the speeding tickets.
超速罚单。
Yeah, of course.
是的，当然。
I can't imagine renting one of those cars and not getting a speeding ticket.
我无法想象租了其中一辆车而不收到超速罚单。
Exactly.
没错。
So if any of you out there have experience renting cars or you have some questions about
所以如果你们中有人有租车经验，或者对。
the specifics that are involved in this process, let us know on our website, EnglishPod.com.
这个过程涉及的具体细节有疑问，请在我们的网站EnglishPod.com上告诉我们。
Right.
没错。
We'll be happy to answer any questions or doubts and we'll see you guys there.
我们很乐意回答任何问题或疑惑，到时候见。
All right.
好的。
Until next time, everyone.
各位，下次再见。
Thanks for listening to EnglishPod.
感谢收听 EnglishPod。